<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ignacio Saldivia Gonzatti</title>
    <link>https://www.ignaciosg.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ignacio Saldivia Gonzatti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Ignacio Saldivia Gonzatti</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ignaciosg.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://www.ignaciosg.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ignaciosg.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>Projects I contributed to that have been published in peer-reviewed journals&#xA;Spenger, C., Saldivia Gonzatti, I., Kröger, L., Fleet, C. R., Voss, R., &amp;amp; Rickels, W. (2024). Strong versus weak sustainable development in the blue economy: a study of 15 EU coastal countries. npj Ocean Sustainability, 3(1), 48. 10.1038/s44183-024-00082-6&#xA;Saldivia Gonzatti, I., Jannes, G., &amp;amp; Barreal, J. (2022). Factors influencing the rate of sorted solid waste collection: An empirical analysis towards local management in Catalonia (NE Spain).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MSc Thesis</title>
      <link>https://www.ignaciosg.com/project/thesismsc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ignaciosg.com/project/thesismsc/</guid>
      <description>I conducted my MSc thesis at the Environmental Economics and Natural Resources Group at Wageningen University &amp;amp; Research. I did fieldwork in Costa Rica, where I interviewed pineapple farmers, researchers, and government officials. I studied the current state of pineapple leaves valorisation in Costa Rica, analyzed the barriers preventing the adoption of valorisation processes and the transition to a circular bioeconomy, and proposed a Facility Location Problem optimization model to improve the current situation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://www.ignaciosg.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ignaciosg.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.&#xA;Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>https://www.ignaciosg.com/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ignaciosg.com/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes A A A A A A A A 6rem&#xA;(96px) 5rem&#xA;(80px) 3rem&#xA;(48px) 2.25rem&#xA;(36px) 1.5rem&#xA;(24px) 1.25rem&#xA;(20px) 1rem&#xA;(16px) .875rem&#xA;(14px) Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.ignaciosg.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ignaciosg.com/resume/</guid>
      <description> Download in PDF </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>https://www.ignaciosg.com/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ignaciosg.com/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the folks who have contributed both technical and creative skills to this project:&#xA;Desirée De Leon &amp;#x1f992; (designed 5 of the custom color themes, made illustrations for the workshop, and provided general aesthetic feedback along the way)&#xA;Garrick Aden-Buie &amp;#x1f9d9; (debugged headroom.js and lent his panelset.js code to the theme)&#xA;Allison Horst &amp;#x1f415; (awesome illustrations of campfires, seedlings, and evergreens, as well as my R Markdown hedgehog mascot &amp;#x1f994;)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://www.ignaciosg.com/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ignaciosg.com/license/</guid>
      <description>All my posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
