<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Anthology on Ignacio Saldivia Gonzatti</title>
    <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Anthology on Ignacio Saldivia Gonzatti</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Ignacio Saldivia Gonzatti</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:42727/anthology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Colón</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/a-col%C3%B3n/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/a-col%C3%B3n/</guid>
      <description>¡Desgraciado Almirante! Tu pobre América,&#xA;tu india virgen y hermosa de sangre cálida,&#xA;la perla de tus sueños, es una histérica&#xA;de convulsivos nervios y frente pálida.&#xA;Un desastroso espirítu posee tu tierra:&#xA;donde la tribu unida blandió sus mazas,&#xA;hoy se enciende entre hermanos perpetua guerra,&#xA;se hieren y destrozan las mismas razas.&#xA;Al ídolo de piedra reemplaza ahora&#xA;el ídolo de carne que se entroniza,&#xA;y cada día alumbra la blanca aurora</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A veces quiero preguntarte cosas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/a-veces-quiero-preguntarte-cosas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/a-veces-quiero-preguntarte-cosas/</guid>
      <description>A veces quiero preguntarte cosas, y me intimidas tU con la mirada, y retorno al silencio contagiada del timido perfume de tus rosas.&#xA;A veces quise no sofiar contigo,&#xA;y cuanto mas queria mas sofiaba, por tus versos que yo saboreaba,&#xA;tu el rico de poemas, yo el mendigo.&#xA;Pero yo no adivino lo que invento,&#xA;y nunca inventaré lo que adivino&#xA;del nombre esclavo de mi pensamiento. Adivino que no soy tu contento,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Al fin termino por entender  (Caracas, 1959)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/al-fin-termino-por-entender-caracas-1959/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/al-fin-termino-por-entender-caracas-1959/</guid>
      <description>Al fin termino por entender&#xA;que yo amo esta ciudad hasta la rabia:&#xA;es tierra y abono para la nostalgia.&#xA;benditos constructores que no dejan ni una casa,&#xA;amadísimos urbanistas paisajistas&#xA;que siempre cambian los bancos de las plazas&#xA;(nada conserva su nombre&#xA;y lo agradezco de todo corazón)&#xA;que nada se acerque a la eternidad,&#xA;que la ciudad que yo conozco&#xA;no la conozcan mis hijos,&#xA;que nunca rodemos por la misma calle,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bye Bye Baidi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/bye-bye-baidi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/bye-bye-baidi/</guid>
      <description>Bye Bye Baidi, by Li Ba i&#xA;Here’s a tongue in cheek translation.&#xA;**Bye Bye Baidi, by Li Bai&#xA;下江陵&#xA;Xia Jiangling&#xA;**&#xA;A sea of colorful clouds&#xA;Was there to see me off,&#xA;The world awaits,&#xA;As I Li Bai,&#xA;Left Baidi.&#xA;It was the crack of dawn.&#xA;It was three hundred miles,&#xA;To reach Jiangling,&#xA;A thousand li,&#xA;If one counts in Chinese.&#xA;Along the way, on both banks,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deep Thoughts at Ulta Beauty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/deep-thoughts-at-ulta-beauty/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/deep-thoughts-at-ulta-beauty/</guid>
      <description>I went to Ulta Beauty to buy perfume I was horny and I wanted the universe inside my nose The lit shelves and raised hair Press a sensual towering cloud Swells and pitches of blood This one smells like observation deck This one smells like Florida toilet Stinky zoo Albino gator There was no tester for Ariana Grande’s “thank u next” signature scent I Googled its reviews: “Smells like sexy pickles and pears” We had everything on earth Pupae, larvae, tiger moths Stick bugs and shrimp plants and giant millipedes, jellyfish And what did we make Dell computer oxycodone maxi dresses Water beds, the PT Cruiser P90X, MK ULTRA, bitcoin, body rock, nation states We could have had manta rays But we wanted Boone’s Farm apple wine I’m depressed I’m depressed by mankind’s infinite reach</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doesn&#39;t Every Poet Write a Poem About Unrequited Love</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/doesnt-every-poet-write-a-poem-about-unrequited-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/doesnt-every-poet-write-a-poem-about-unrequited-love/</guid>
      <description>The flowers I wanted to bring you, wild and wet from the pale dunes&#xA;and still smelling of the summer night, and still holding a moment or two of the night cricket&#39;s humble prayer, would have been so handsome in your hands-- so happy--I dare to say it-- in your hands-- yet your smile would have been nowhere and maybe you would have tossed them onto the ground, or maybe, for tenderness, you would have taken them into your house and given them water put them in a dark corner out of reach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EVERY DOG&#39;S STORY</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/every-dogs-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/every-dogs-story/</guid>
      <description>I have a bed, my very own. It&amp;rsquo;s just my size. And sometimes I like to sleep alone with dreams inside my eyes.&#xA;But sometimes dreams are dark and wild and creepy and I wake and am afraid, though I don&amp;rsquo;t know why. But I&amp;rsquo;m no longer sleepy and too slowly the hours go by.&#xA;So I climb on the bed where the light of the moon is shining on your face and I know it will be morning soon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>father, you always call to say nothing in particular.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/father-you-always-call-to-say-nothing-in-particular/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/father-you-always-call-to-say-nothing-in-particular/</guid>
      <description>father. you always call to say nothing in particular. you ask what i&amp;rsquo;m doing or where i am and when the silence stretches like a lifetime between us i scramble to find questions to keep the conversation going. what i long to say most is. i understand this world broke you. it has been so hard on your feet. i don&amp;rsquo;t blame you for not knowing how to remain soft with me.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Amores imposibles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/from-amores-imposibles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/from-amores-imposibles/</guid>
      <description>Todos los amores imposibles son eternos, el tiempo no los toca y no existen traiciones entre los amores imposibles. Amo con toda intensidad, amo sin límites a cada uno de mis amores imposibles. A veces el olor del café trastoca el orden de los años y voy a dar a la madrugada de un resplandor que a mí me alumbra o de pronto la voz de Janis Joplin me ensarta en una noche cítrica, de alambre, la noche del hechizo, puede ser una forma precisa de mecerse el viento entre los árboles y la danza del cuerpo, la eterna danza de un cuerpo eterno entre la eterna danza de la brisa.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Emotional Intelligence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/from-emotional-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/from-emotional-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;&amp;lsquo;Beyond this possibility looms a pressing moral imperative. These are times when the fabric of society seems to unravel at ever-greater speed, when selfishness, violence, and a meanness of spirit seem to be rotting the goodness of our communal lives. Here the argument for the importance of emotional intelligence hinges on the link between sentiment, character, and moral instincts. There is growing evidence that fundamental ethical stances in life stem from underlying emotional capacities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Nietzsche</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/from-nietzsche/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/from-nietzsche/</guid>
      <description>However, even &amp;ldquo;boredom&amp;rdquo; has its aura of mystery and is imbued with a singular pathos by Nietzsche. Boredom, from which art provides a refuge, becomes terrifying—the yawning abyss of being. When people are bored, they regard the moment as an empty passage of time. External events, as well as people&amp;rsquo;s sense of self, become inconsequential. The phases of life lose their intentional tension and cave in on themselves like a soufflé removed from the oven too soon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From No Name in the Street</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/from-no-name-in-the-street/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/from-no-name-in-the-street/</guid>
      <description>“People pay for what they do, and still more for what they have allowed themselves to become, and they pay for it, very simply, by the lives they lead.”</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Primeval and Other Times</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/from-primeval-and-other-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/from-primeval-and-other-times/</guid>
      <description>There are two kinds of learning, from the inside and from the outside. The first is regarded as the best, or even the only kind. And so people learn through distant journeys, watching, reading, universities and lectures —- they learn from what is happening outside them. Man is a stupid creature who has to learn. So he tacks knowledge onto him- self, he gathers it like a bee, gaining more and more of it, putting it to use and processing it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From The Theatre and Its Double</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/from-the-theatre-and-its-double/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/from-the-theatre-and-its-double/</guid>
      <description>We cannot live forever surrounded by the dead and by death.&#xA;And if there are still prejudices, they must be destroyed.&#xA;THE DUTY&#xA;I say well&#xA;THE DUTY&#xA;of the writer, of the poet, it is not to cowardly shut oneself away in a text, a book,&#xA;a magazine of those who will never come out again, but rather go outside&#xA;to shake&#xA;to attack&#xA;to the public spirit&#xA;if not</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I am worried</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/i-am-worried/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/i-am-worried/</guid>
      <description>I worried a lot. Will the garden grow, will the rivers flow in the right direction, will the earth turn&#xA;as it was taught, and if not how shall&#xA;I correct it?&#xA;Was I right, was I wrong, will I be forgiven, can I do better?&#xA;Will I ever be able to sing, even the sparrows can do it and I am, well, hopeless.&#xA;Is my eyesight fading or am I just imagining it, am I going to get rheumatism, lockjaw, dementia?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I fear a Man of frugal Speech</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/i-fear-a-man-of-frugal-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/i-fear-a-man-of-frugal-speech/</guid>
      <description>I fear a Man of frugal Speech— I fear a Silent Man— Haranguer—I can overtake— Or Babbler—entertain— But He who weigheth—While the Rest— Expend their furthest pound— Of this Man—I am wary— I fear that He is Grand</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I sit and look out</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/i-sit-and-look-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/i-sit-and-look-out/</guid>
      <description>| sit and look out upon all the sorrows of the world, and upon all oppression and shame&#xA;| hear secret convulsive sobs from young men at anguish with themselves, remorseful after deeds done,&#xA;| see in low life the mother misused by her children, dying, neglected, gaunt,desperate&#xA;| see the wife misused by her husband, | see the treacherous seducer of young women&#xA;| mark the ranklings of jealousy and unrequited love attempted to be hid, | see these sights on the earth</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>La inutilidad de dar consejos (O Filatelista, O Mendigo e Outros Contos )</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/la-inutilidad-de-dar-consejos-o-filatelista-o-mendigo-e-outros-contos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/la-inutilidad-de-dar-consejos-o-filatelista-o-mendigo-e-outros-contos/</guid>
      <description>Yo no aconsejo. Colecciono sellos. Para dar consejos, es necesario estar completamente seguro de que los consejos son buenos y, para eso, es necesario estar seguro (de lo que nadie en absoluto lo está) de estar en posesión de la verdad. Y luego es necesario saber si esos consejos se adaptan al individuo al que se le dan, para lo cual es necesario conocer toda su alma, lo que casi nunca es posible.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LA MEDIDA DE MI MADRE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/la-medida-de-mi-madre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/la-medida-de-mi-madre/</guid>
      <description>No sé si lo he dicho: mi madre es pequeña y tiene que ponerse de puntillas para besarme. Hace años yo me empinaba, supongo, para robarle un beso. Nos hemos pasado la vida estirándonos y agachándonos para buscar la medida exacta donde podemos querernos.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lluvia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/lluvia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/lluvia/</guid>
      <description>hoy llueve mucho, mucho,&#xA;y pareciera que están lavando el mundo&#xA;mi vecino de al lado mira la lluvia&#xA;y piensa escribir una carta de amor/&#xA;una carta a la mujer que vive con él&#xA;y le cocina y le lava la ropa y hace el amor con él&#xA;y se parece a su sombra/&#xA;mi vecino nunca le dice palabras de amor a la&#xA;mujer/&#xA;entra a la casa por la ventana y no por la puerta/</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Los espejos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/los-espejos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/los-espejos/</guid>
      <description>No los domésticos,&#xA;estratégicamente dispuestos&#xA;para que te digan siempre&#xA;lo que quieres oír,&#xA;sino los otros,&#xA;los que no tienen dueño,&#xA;los de los bares,&#xA;los de los comercios,&#xA;los de los vestíbulos de hotel,&#xA;esos son los que te dicen la verdad:&#xA;que no eres nada, nadie,&#xA;en realidad,&#xA;solo uno más&#xA;que pasaba por allí.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mad Girl&#39;s Love Song</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/mad-girls-love-song/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/mad-girls-love-song/</guid>
      <description>I shut my eyes and all the world drops dead;&#xA;I lift my lids and all is born again.&#xA;(I think I made you up inside my head.)&#xA;The stars go waltzing out in blue and red,&#xA;And arbitrary blackness gallops in:&#xA;I shut my eyes and all the world drops dead.&#xA;I dreamed that you bewitched me into bed&#xA;And sung me moon-struck, kissed me quite insane.&#xA;(I think I made you up inside my head.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nigth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/nigth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/nigth/</guid>
      <description>I love the silent hour of night,&#xA;For blissful dreams may then arise,&#xA;Revealing to my charmed sight&#xA;What may not bless my waking eyes.&#xA;And then a voice may meet my ear,&#xA;That death has silenced long ago;&#xA;And hope and rapture may appear&#xA;Instead of solitude and woe.&#xA;Cold in the grave for years has lain&#xA;The form it was my bliss to see;&#xA;And only dreams can bring again,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Aging</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/on-aging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/on-aging/</guid>
      <description>When you see me sitting quietly, Like a sack left on the shelf, Don&amp;rsquo;t think | need your chattering. I&amp;rsquo;m listening to myself.&#xA;Hold! Stop! Don&amp;rsquo;t pity me!&#xA;Hold! Stop your sympathy! Understanding if you got it, Otherwise I&amp;rsquo;ll do without it!&#xA;When my bones are stiff and aching, And my feet won&amp;rsquo;t climb the stair,&#xA;| will only ask one favor:&#xA;Don&amp;rsquo;t bring me no rocking chair. When you see me walking, stumbling, Don&amp;rsquo;t study and get it wrong.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On altering memories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/on-altering-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/on-altering-memories/</guid>
      <description>¿También nos engañamos con respecto a los recuerdos de nuestra propia vida?&#xA;Sí. Son datos que están ya demostrados científicamente. Cuando almacenamos algo en la memoria a largo plazo, la manera para recordar es extraer este recuerdo de la memoria a largo plazo y ponerlo al frente del almacenamiento a corto plazo. ¿Qué ocurre? Que cuando extraemos este recuerdo y lo situamos ahí, de repente se vuelve versátil. El propio hecho de acceder a ese recuerdo hace que lo cambies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On buying and reading books</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/on-buying-and-reading-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/on-buying-and-reading-books/</guid>
      <description>It is foolish to think that you have to read all the books you buy, as it is foolish to criticize those who buy more books than they will ever be able to read. It would be like saying that you should use all the cutlery or glasses or screwdrivers or drill bits you bought before buying new ones.&#xA;There are things in life that we need to always have plenty of supplies, even if we will only use a small portion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On food aid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/on-food-aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/on-food-aid/</guid>
      <description>Those who come with wheat, millet, corn or milk, they are not helping us. Those who really want to help us can give us ploughs, tractors, fertilizers, insecticides, watering cans, drills and dams. That is how we would define food aid.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On talking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/on-talking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/on-talking/</guid>
      <description>And then a scholar said, Speak of Talking. And he answered, saying: You talk when you cease to be at peace with your thoughts; And when you can no longer dwell in the solitude of your heart you live in your lips, and sound is a diversion and a pastime. And in much of your talking, thinking is half murdered. For thought is a bird of space, that in a cage of words may indeed unfold its wings but cannot fly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Riverbank</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/riverbank/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/riverbank/</guid>
      <description>(Translated from the Chinese)&#xA;One white, one red, one black Three horses are drinking at the riverbank&#xA;They drink at their own pace, some up Some down Sometimes their heads reach the river&#xA;At the same time&#xA;As if a river were flowing Out of their mouths&#xA;As their minds flow from the river source Still innocent, clear, undisturbed&#xA;The sun is setting slowly A man watches, without blinking&#xA;How a river disappears into the night Held in the mouths of three horses</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Screenshot_20200301-222507</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/screenshot_20200301-222507/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/screenshot_20200301-222507/</guid>
      <description>-Leer te hace ver más lejos, te hace ver a los ojos de los otros, como iguales, sean del sexo que sean, la religión que sea, la condición social que tengan. Leer abre tu mente y no permite que se llene de polvosos prejuicios, de malas inten- ciones, de ideas preconcebidas. Pero lo lamento, no te hace ser mejor a menos que quieras ser mejor.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silencio by Eloy Blanco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/silencio-by-eloy-blanco/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/silencio-by-eloy-blanco/</guid>
      <description>Cuando tú te quedes muda, cuando yo me quede ciego, nos quedarán las manos y el silencio.&#xA;Cuando tú te pongas vieja, cuando yo me ponga viejo, nos quedarán los labios y el silencio.&#xA;Cuando tú te quedes muerta, cuando yo me quede muerto, tendrán que enterrarnos juntos y en silencio;&#xA;y cuando tú resucites, cuando yo viva de nuevo, nos volveremos a amar en silencio;&#xA;y cuando todo se acabe por siempre en el universo, será un silencio de amor el silencio.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silencio by Neruda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/silencio-by-neruda/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/silencio-by-neruda/</guid>
      <description>Yo que crecí dentro de un árbol&#xA;tendría mucho que decir,&#xA;pero aprendí tanto silencio&#xA;que tengo mucho que callar&#xA;y eso se conoce creciendo&#xA;sin otro goce que crecer,&#xA;sin más pasión que la substancia,&#xA;sin más acción que la inocencia,&#xA;y por dentro el tiempo dorado&#xA;hasta que la altura lo llama&#xA;para convertirlo en naranja.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Globe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/the-globe/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/the-globe/</guid>
      <description>After my sons grew up and moved away, a globe of the world, cradled in its caliper,&#xA;remained high up on a shelf in their room, where it had been already for many years.&#xA;Rounder than we know the earth to be, the globe marks boundaries that have since dissolved,&#xA;while the colors that denote those stitched-together places, remain bright, if arbitrary, except the green-blue&#xA;seas.&#xA;So much about a globe is obvious, so much obscure, and yet reaching up to take it down to pack away</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The hurting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/the-hurting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/the-hurting/</guid>
      <description>when my mother opens her mouth to have a conversation at dinner my father shoves the word hush between her lips and tells her to never speak with her mouth full. this is how the women in my family learned to live with their mouths closed.&#xA;you plough into me with two fingers and i am mostly shocked. it feels like rubber against an open wound. i do not like it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mango</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/the-mango/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/the-mango/</guid>
      <description>One evening&#xA;I met the mango.&#xA;At first there were four or five of them&#xA;in a bowl.&#xA;They looked like stones you find&#xA;in the rivers of Pennsylvania&#xA;when the waters are low.&#xA;That size, and almost round.&#xA;Mossy green.&#xA;But this was a rich house, and clever too. After salmon and salads,&#xA;mangoes for everyone appeared on blue plates, each one cut in half and scored&#xA;and shoved forward from its rind, like an orange flower, cubist and juicy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Title of the Quote or Poem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/template/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/template/</guid>
      <description>Paste the content of the quote or poem here.&#xA;This can be multiple lines and paragraphs.&#xA;It supports markdown formatting like bold and italic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upon Arrival</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/upon-arrival/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/upon-arrival/</guid>
      <description>You will need to state the reason for your visit. Don&amp;rsquo;t say because I want to walk down old roads and caress stone walls the color of my skin.&#xA;You will need to state the reason for your visit. Dont say because the olives are ready for harvest and I will coax the fruit from the trees, press it into liquid gold.&#xA;You will need to state the reason for your visit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Viceversa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/viceversa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/viceversa/</guid>
      <description>Tengo miedo de verte&#xA;necesidad de verte&#xA;esperanza de verte&#xA;desazones de verte&#xA;tengo ganas de hallarte&#xA;preocupación de hallarte&#xA;certidumbre de hallarte&#xA;pobres dudas de hallarte&#xA;tengo urgencia de oírte&#xA;alegría de oírte&#xA;buena suerte de oírte&#xA;y temores de oírte&#xA;o sea&#xA;resumiendo&#xA;estoy jodido&#xA;y radiante&#xA;quizá más lo primero&#xA;que lo segundo&#xA;y también&#xA;viceversa.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Are Your Poems So Dark</title>
      <link>http://localhost:42727/anthology/why-are-your-poems-so-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:42727/anthology/why-are-your-poems-so-dark/</guid>
      <description>Isn&amp;rsquo;t the moon dark too, most of the time?&#xA;And doesn&amp;rsquo;t the white page seem unfinished&#xA;without the dark stain of alphabets?&#xA;When God demanded light, he didn&amp;rsquo;t banish darkness.&#xA;Instead he invented ebony and crows&#xA;and that small mole on your left cheekbone.&#xA;Or did you mean to ask &amp;ldquo;Why are you sad so often?&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Ask the moon. Ask what it has witnessed.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
